Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
This all started with you.
Lingrong wasn't involved at all.
But now, she has gone to the Cold Palace
and had Yu strangled.
That's not the girl I know.
I thought she was more delicate.
Even a rabbit bites when it's cornered.
Su Peisheng didn't even know what to do,
but Lingrong handled it so sharply.
That's what surprises me most.
It was a surprise.
But nevertheless, Lingrong did it for us.
You're right.
But I keep thinking that she is not the person I see every day.
Is she finally dead?
Completely and utterly.
Someone saw her body
being dragged the mass grave pit.
They were ruthless.
Her neck was almost snapped off.
It was so frightful.
The castrated certainly know how to use a knife.
But you can't blame them.
It was her fault for offending His Majesty's servants.
It serves her right.
Did she divulge anything?
Not a single word.
Sensible.
We underestimated that sickly Zhen Huan.
We'll see what the future holds.
Looks like it's finally going to rain after all these stuffy days.
Jinxi.
My Lady, why are you still awake?
I feel a bit scared.
The tales told about spirits
are just silly rumors.
Don't take them to heart.
I'm not afraid of ghosts.
I'm afraid that...
even though Yu is dead, this situation isn't over yet.
My Lady, do you suspect that
someone else was behind this.
If you think about it, Yu did not have the mind to plot and scheme.
She came to the palace as a maid.
How did she know about medicine?
She had to know about the dosage,
and she had to coordinate with the servants
both inside and outside my palace walls.
And where did she get the herbs?
True.
My Lady, you should have kept her alive for interrogation.
She hated me to the bone.
She wouldn't have said anything.
She might even have accused us of slander.
But now that she's dead,
the people behind her might lower their guard
and we might have a chance to find them.
If so, let us put on a good show about Yu's death.
Ghost... A ghost!
A ghost!
Are we almost there?
Yes, My Lady.
My Lady, you must be tired after chanting sutras
at Baohua Hall all night.
The Empress has been unwell.
It is the duty of a concubine to pray for Her Majesty.
Who's crying?
It sends chills down my spine. Go faster!
A ghost!
A ghost... There's a ghost!
Did you really see it?
Lady Fuca, you were praying all night.
Maybe that caused your vision to blur?
If you don't believe me, ask Sang'er.
She saw it too.
I did... It was the long hair of a woman...
...cold as ice...
...and the stench... like a dead body...
See? Sang'er is scared out of her wits.
She is my smartest maid.
Yes... I heard that a eunuch saw it as well.
Now he is sick from fright.
It was real...
...a white dress... her face as pale as death...
... her tongue was so long... and it was dripping blood...
... blood was coming from her eyes too...
Her hair was down, and she kept crying...and crying...
I wonder if she was crying
because she suffered an injustice.
Companion An, you don't speak very much.
But when you do, you speak to the point.
If not for an injustice,
why would she cry at midnight?
Injustice?
It must be Yu who died in the Cold Palace.
She came back for vengeance.
Don't say that. She ought to
die a thousand deaths for her offense.
What do you know?
She refused to commit suicide
and that was causing trouble for Mr. Su.
So she was strangled with a bowstring.
The harem is in turmoil.
We have to wait for His Majesty to return.
We will report it to him.
His Majesty dislikes hearing any tales about ghosts.
You can tell him... if you dare.
"Every injustice has its perpetrator."
I did nothing to her!
Why did she come for me?
That is why she left without hurting you.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be sitting here right now.
So, who do you think Yu is coming after?
This has nothing to do with Sourire.
I heard that Yu's death has caused Lady Sourire
many sleepless nights.
Have the doctors visited her?
I thank Your Highness for your concern.
Dr. Wen has been treating her.
But she hasn't shown any sign of improvement.
The palace is haunted by a ghost these days.
Over a dozen people have seen it.
We can't be at peace.
I heard that several eunuchs were bed-ridden out of fear
and Lady Fuca doesn't even dare to step out of her chamber.
His Majesty says that the wise do not engage
in stories of ghosts and unnnatural forces.
With so many self-proclaimed witnesses,
the story gets grander and more embellished each time.
It has been so long since His Majesty last visited
Consort Astuce - she must have forgotten what he says.
You Highness hears His Majesty's wisdom frequently,
unlike us leading a lonely existence in the palace.
The rumors wouldn't spread
if we all were as blessed as Your Highness.
Unfortunately, we are not.
If you are not blessed, pray harder.
Otherwise, when the vengeful ghost comes,
even the Buddha won't be able to save you.
I can't imagine how absurd you all must sound in private -
mouths full of devils and ghosts.
I don't believe any of that.
Yu will only come after who she hated in life.
Is this anyone else's concern?
I thank Your Highness for the advice.
Yu committed the crime all by herself,
and she ought to reap what she sowed.
But if she was instigated by someone else,
she is most likely to come after whoever exploited her.
She will interrogate them about why she was used as their dagger.
Your Majesty looks better today.
It is my duty to pray to the Shamanic Gods
on the first day of every month.
I feel much better because of Heaven's blessings.
Your Majesty has been sick. You might not have been informed
that ghost stories have prevailed in the harem lately.
We should not lend credence to rumors.
The Forbidden City has never been short of
old wives' tales over the past hundreds of years.
If people are taking it seriously,
an exorcism should be performed.
Wouldn't an exorcism convince people of their superstitions?
Exorcism is not about convincing them,
but putting their minds at ease.
In that case, the priests at Baohua Hall
shall perform the "Water and Land Ritual" night and day.
Have the priests focus on those who died in the Cold Palace.
The priests shall pray and bring their souls to liberation.
I thank Your Majesty for waiving my attendance
during the past few days as I have been unwell.
You look much better today.
I remember that you looked pale a few days ago.
I thank Your Majesty for caring.
It is my duty to pay respects to Your Majesty daily.
I hope Your Majesty will pardon my negligence.
- Have a seat.
- I thank Your Majesty.
You haven't been well since you entered the palace.
I don't have the heart to make you come every day.
Of course, it is better to come out during the day.
It would be too bad if you saw those filthy things
walking out at night.
Your Majesty, it's thundering outside.
I'm afraid a thunderstorm is coming soon.
That will make it inconvenient to go out.
The hour is late. You are dismissed.
I bid Your Majesty a goodbye.
Why didn't Lady Cao come today?
Princess Wenyi caught a cold.
She needs to stay with her.
I bid Your Highness Consort Fleur goodbye.
I bid Your Highness Concubine Beauté goodbye.
Lady Sourire, even though you've been feeling better,
you still look very pale.
I hope you're not suffering too much
from your haunting nightmares.
Your Highness must not speak of it.
It haunts anyone who does.
You must be scared out your wits,
daring to speak such nonsense to me!
Your Highness, please forgive her.
Sourire is truly very afraid.
In fact...
In fact, many people have seen it.
So we have to be careful.
Yes, exactly! I saw it too!
Why would Her Majesty have exorcisms performed
if the ghost was just our imagination?
The ghost seems extremely hostile.
I wonder if the priests can stop it.
The exorcists can't stop it?
Her death was brutal. She must be bitterly resentful.
They say, "Although the Buddha rises to one,
the Devil rises to ten."
I heard that when His Majesty granted her suicide,
not a single concubine close to her pleaded in her favor.
That is why she had to die miserably in the Cold Palace.
That's why she holds a grudge.
I would expect to hear such words from the servants.
But for concubines to repeat these things, how disgracful!
It truly isn't our place to say such things.
However, everyone has been in a panic lately.
Lady Cao is very brave.
I would feel better if she was accompanying Your Highness tonight.
I wonder why she's absent.
Princess Wenyi caught a cold.
Lady Cao needs to look after her.
That is why she didn't come to pay her respects.
Lady Sourire is very thoughtful.
But, I'm afraid you are overthinking.
- Let's get going.
- Certainly.
"A clear conscience does not fear the ghosts knocking on the door."
Let's go quickly.
It's very dark now.
What if the filthy things come out later?
It's about to rain.
We should go quickly.
What was that?
What was what?
- What was it?
- What's wrong?
A ghost!
She's here! She's coming for me!
- It's Concubine Beauté?
- It is.
Jinxi, report to Her Majesty.
Let's go check it out.
A ghost... A ghost!
It's late!
What are you shrieking about?
Shut your mouth now!
A ghost ... A ghost ... A ghost!
She's here!
She's here, isn't she?
Shut your mouth or I'll send you to the Cold Palace!
What are you waiting for? Help her up!
Not me! It wasn't me!
The medicine... I got her the medicine...
I didn't ask her to poison Lady Sourire! Not me!
She's gone insane.
Cover her mouth and take her to my palace!
Hold on!
I hope Your Highness will reconsider.
It is not clear yet what has just happened.
I think that we should send Concubine Beauté
back to her palace and summon the imperial doctors immediately.
Why should she go to Your Highness's palace?
Concubine Beauté has lost her manners
and should not be seen in public.
It'll be more convenient if she stays in my palace.
I agree with Your Highness.
But in my opinion, such an emergency must
first be reported to Her Majesty.
We have to act expediently.
I'm afraid Concubine Beauté's insane words
will soil Her Majesty's ears.
We can report to her later.
I assist the Empress in managing the palace.
Don't you think I can make this decision?
This is a matter of consequence concerning
the head concubine of a palace.
I'm afraid His Majesty would place the blame on Your Highness
if the Empress was not informed.
Even though you are in high favor,
you shouldn't use His Majesty against me.
Are the two of you deliberately making things
difficult for me?
Your Highness, I have no intention of that.
Concubine Beauté's words
involved Yu's scheme to poison me.
As the victim of this incident,
I have to take extra precautions .
Why are you still standing there? Take her back!
Her Majesty the Empress.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Peace to Your Majesty.
All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
How could I have a moment of peace with all of this
commotion in the harem.
What happened to Concubine Beauté?
Zhou Ninghai, you are a servant!
How dare you put your hand on her mouth?
What an offense to your superior!
Your Majesty may not know.
Concubine Beauté lost her mind and started to speak nonsense.
I asked my servant to quiet her down
so her words would not disturb the other concubines.
But you must let go of her!
Or will she walk back to her palace with her mouth covered?
- Your Highness! Help me!
- What are you doing?
Yu came for me!
I didn't make her do it! I didn't!
Let go of Her Highness!
No, it has nothing to do with anyone else.
It was her own fault.
Don't be scared. Yu wasn't here.
Go with me quickly.
Yu is here! She's here!
She's coming after us!
Nonsense!
Help me! Your Majesty!
A ghost! A ghost!
Such disgraceful nonsense!
I cannot be at peace with you like this.
- Jiang Fuhai.
- Yes.
Bring her to the Palace of Great Benevolence.
Your Majesty.
It seems that Concubine Beauté has gone insane.
How can I let her disturb Your Majesty all night?
It's better if I take care of her for tonight.
I have many chambers in my palace.
There is certainly a place for Concubine Beauté.
More importantly, although she is not in her right mind,
she revealed her involvement in Yu's crime.
This is a matter of great consequence
and I must investigate.
Do you see anything wrong with Concubine Beauté staying in my palace?
Of course I see nothing improper with
Your Majesty taking care of her.
His Majesty entrusted me to assist you,
and I only wished to spare Your Majesty of this burden.
Otherwise, His Majesty would blame me
for being inconsiderate.
Your Majesty is the head of the harem.
His Majesty will be more assured if you look after this matter.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Jiang Fuhai, bring along Concubine Beauté.
Yes.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组👻
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
My Lady... My Ladies, you're finally back.
It took you so long to return.
We were very worried.
Xiao-Yunzi.
Sorry that you had to play the ghost.
My Lady, you flatter me.
But I did look at myself in the mirror.
And my reflection even startled me.
I'm sure it did!
You frightened Concubine Beauté so much
that her secrets spilled out!
I'm glad that my little tricks could be useful.
I must thank Jade for making the white costume
and Companion An for painting my big white face!
My face painting was nothing compared to the plan you two came up with.
No, it was you who came up with the brilliant idea.
Huan'er and I just added a few more details.
You won't blame me for being too cruel, will you?
I only did all of this to keep us safe.
Why would we?
We are all sisters. Why would we say that?
Meizhuang, will you blame me?
You're the most observant of all of us. You noticed
that Concubine Beauté was petrified of ghosts.
All right, that's enough conversation.
Xiao-Yunzi, burn the costume.
We cannot leave any trace behind.
Yes, I understand.
Your Highness, please sit down.
You will exhaust yourself from all of this pacing.
All this time sitting here and you don't have anything else to say?
Cry, cry, cry!
What else can she do?
Why did you bring her here?
Your Highness, please calm your anger.
The princess is sick and needs to be with me.
What use are you in such a crisis?
You can't even come up with a single idea!
Does Your Highness believe in ghosts?
The ghost doesn't dare to approach you
because you don't believe.
But Concubine Beauté is not as strong as she appears.
That's why a hoax could break her down.
A hoax?
You mean the ghost was a hoax?
Otherwise, why did the ghost only attack
Concubine Beauté but not Your Highness?
It was Zhen Huan. It must be her.
Shen Meizhuang doesn't have such wicked tricks.
Very well, she dares to create a ghost hoax.
I will turn her palace upside down
to find her little hoax tricks.
No, Your Highness.
Your Highness must not do that.
Your Highness is already under suspicion.
To search her palace would bring you nothing
but more trouble.
And Zhen Huan must have already destroyed the evidence.
Your search would reveal nothing.
So am I supposed sit just here and wait?
Fortunately, Concubine Beauté has already gone insane, hasn't she?
Of course! That is why she's speaking nonsense!
Speaking nonsense...
How can anyone believe the words of a madwoman?
A madwoman's words are not to be trusted.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
I summoned you all so early in the morning because
I wish to know the details of what happened last night.
Her Majesty the Empress Dowager.
I bow in respect before Your Majesty.
Peace to Your Majesty.
All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Consort Fleur came to inform
that Concubine Beauté is unwell.
I've come to visit her.
Why was the Empress Dowager brought into this matter?
It must be Consort Fleur trying to
disentangle herself from suspicion.
That was very bold of her.
The Empress Dowager is related to the Empress.
She will take the side of the Empress.
Consort Fleur must be very confident.
Her confidence cannot compare to a blood relation.
The Empress Dowager is certainly displeased that
the Empress has been overshadowed by Consort Fleur.
In the wake of last night's commotion,
all eyes are watching the Palace of Great Benevolence.
But nothing has happened.
When I was a child,
I heard that there is always a calm before the storm.
Your Majesty must have grown tired
after hearing all of the nonsense this morning.
Please take a break and have some tea.
I rarely get to hear these types of... unique stories.
Your Majesty need not pay attention to it.
I will ask the doctors to take great care of Concubine Beauté.
There's no need.
What she's saying now is already unbearable.
Her words will only be less pleasant to hear if she recovers.
She will be sent to the Cold Palace
to keep your palace clean.
Yes, I will arrange her relocation tomorrow.
How useless she is to have broken down from this small fright.
"A guilty conscience needs no accuser" indeed.
But Concubine Beauté said that
Consort Fleur was behind this.
So what? She is not in her right her mind.
Your Majesty...
I know Consort Fleur has been overstepping
your authority all these years.
She never holds back.
She's been reckless
ever since she married into the family.
But the Emperor likes her,
and her brother is Nian Gengyao.
Concubine Beauté has gone insane,
and no one will trust the words of a madwoman.
Yes.
So we must use a small punishment to prevent bigger mistakes.
You will say that you must manage the harem yourself
in order to stop the rampant rumors.
What if His Majesty ...
When His Majesty returns, I will tell him
that you quelled the rumor and pacified the harem.
As for Lady Sourire, she is smart.
And Lady Shen is reliable.
You may assign tasks to Lady Shen
and have her groomed for palace management.
Yes, they were both selected by you and His Majesty.
Announce my decree that Consort Fleur
will be suspended from her duties.
She will take a break from
assisting in the palace affairs.
Yes.
Jade.
What brought you here?
Greetings, My Lady.
Lady Sourire asked me to get some incense
and burn the sutras she copied as an offering to the Buddha.
Ah, why did Sourire want to offer the sutras?
My Lady said that sutras might bring peace
since the past few days have been eventful.
And for Yu as well.
No matter what Yu did in her life,
my Lady hopes her soul will be liberated quickly.
I should return now.
Please allow me to take my leave.
Certainly.
My Lady.
What's wrong, My Lady?
Sourire copied sutras for Yu.
Does she blame me for killing Yu?
Why would she?
Lady Sourire was also involved in Yu's death.
Why would she blame you?
Don't overthink, My Lady.
We should go.
His Majesty the Emperor.
Your Majesty?
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Rise quickly.
Your Majesty has finally come back.
Sit.
Did you miss me?
I would think of Your Majesty often,
hoping Your Majesty's trip was not too tiring.
I just visited the Empress Dowager and
learned about the conclusion of the poisoning incident.
I feel relieved that you can finally put your mind at ease.
Now that there is a conclusion, I hope Your Majesty will be at ease as well.
Concubine Beauté held a grudge against me
because she cared about Your Majesty.
She cared about me?
Was it me or herself that she cared most about?
Only she knows.
Even if her vicious deeds were because she cared for me,
I won't show mercy on her.
Concubine Beauté has learned the lessons from her mistakes.
Although Consort Fleur was
close with Concubine Beauté,
I don't think Her Highness would
reduce herself to collusion with Concubine Beauté.
Consort Fleur is blessed by Your Majesty and has a resolute mind ...
A resolute mind?
What do you mean by that?
Her Highness is decisive and effective
in making decisions for the harem.
I believe "resolute" can describe Her Highness's
manner of managing the palace affairs.
That can be a double-edged sword.
The Empress Dowager knows what's proper
and rarely interferes in the harem.
But when she does involves herself,
it must be a matter that cannot be ignored.
Her stern punishment aims to clear
the foul and dingy air in the harem.
I only wish that there will be more
understanding and less resentment in the harem
so that Your Majesty can have a peaceful backyard
and concentrate on state affairs.
I heard your father coughing at court.
It seems that he caught a cold.
My father has always had a chronic throat problem.
It worries me a lot.
I asked Su Peisheng to send him some
pei pa koa [herbal syrup] after court.
I am grateful to Your Majesty.
He is your father.
It's also my obligation to care for him.
His condition has always been a concern of my mother.
She makes almond lilly-bulb soup in spring,
and steamed pear with chuan bei in autumn.
She's taken good care of him over the years.
Your parents are a loving couple.
That's why they have a sweet and loving daughter.
Your Majesty teases me.
Mother...
it is the anniversary of your death today.
I wonder if Father remembers.
I wonder if he is...
secretly burning joss paper like I am.
Mother...
I am a useless daughter...
I hope that one day I have a rightful name in the family
and properly offer joss paper to you.
Who could it be at this hour?
What is this?
How dare you burn ghost money in the imperial palace?
Noble Lady Cao.
You... Aren't you the maid of Lady Sourire?
You must know that an
ominous act like this is taboo in the palace.
Burning joss paper is committing Major Disrespect to His Majesty.
Even Lady Sourire cannot save you from this.
Lady Cao, please forgive my offense.
I promise to never do this again.
I beg of you not to tell My Lady.
Never mind, you may rise.
I beg of you to pardon me, Lady Cao.
You are lucky that it was me.
You would already have been sent to the Department of Penalty
if you were caught by someone else.
Now tell me, why are you burning joss paper here?
Today is the anniversary of the death of my mother.
You are a very filial daughter.
But you could do this
secretly in the Palace of Pearl Jade.
Why did you come out here?
I wouldn't dare...
You are the favorite maid of Lady Sourire, aren't you?
She treats you differently from the other servants.
Why wouldn't she allow you to fulfill your filial piety?
I wouldn't dare to offend My Lady.
I beg of you not to let her know, Lady Cao.
I won't then.
Clean up the joss paper quickly.
You will not want to leave the slightest trace.
Thank you, Lady Cao.
[an account book]
1800 taels were spent on the four exorcisms at Baohua Hall.
As the weather is getting hotter, extra mung bean soup
is provided at noon for the servants to relieve the summer heat.
The daily expense is ... 32 taels.
Hold on.
The mung bean soup costs 32 taels a day.
What about a month?
That would be ...
960 taels.
"Wealth begins from frugality."
Even the cost of an extra bowl of mung bean soup
can accumulate a significant cost over time.
I agree with the Empress,
but this expense has existed since the prior emperor.
I'm afraid the servants would complain if it was cut off.
I agree with Your Majesty.
The servants will work harder for a kind master.
This is not an expense to be cut.
Lady Sourire, what do you think?
I know nothing about this.
I will work on my tea
while Meizhuang is working out the numbers.
Sourire sure does know how to live her life comfortably!
Your Majesty, I think that the daily food ration
is more than enough for each palace.
Take a Noble Lady for example:
Every day, I receive two and a half pints of rice,
6 catties of pork, 6 catties of vegetables
[6 catties ≈ 8 lbs ]
2 catties of flour, and one and a half catties of toufu.
[2 catties ≈ 2.5 lbs]
That is too much to ever be consumed within a day.
Not to mention the rations for Concubines and Consorts.
I would suggest we convert the surplus food into extra stipends.
So the rations for mung beans and sugar
will be provided as extra earnings for the servants.
That will save us from making the soup
and everyone will have a fair share
instead of quibbling about others
having more soup than they do.
Meizhuang's idea is brilliant!
I could never calculate all that like her.
It's giving me a headache.
I'm thankful that Lady Shen
is helping me with the calculations.
Your Majesty flatters me.
I would have made every possible mistake
without Your Majesty's patient instructions.
You're new to managing the palace affairs.
Practice will make you perfect.
But not everyone has a natural talent for such practice.
Your Majesty must be talking about me.
I'm naturally untalented.
You all heard that!
What talent have we got
if she isn't considered talented?
I would say that Your Majesty only has yourself to blame
for spoiling Sourire and always letting her speak her mind freely.
I bow in respect before Your Highness.
Rise.
I thank Your Highness.
Tell the Empress that I'm here to pay my respects.
What's wrong? Did you not hear Her Highness's order?
Don't bother then. I'll see myself in.
Her Majesty has a bad migraine today.
She is not able to see Your Highness.
That is exactly why I came to see her.
Despite her physical condition,
Her Majesty seems to be in a good mood.
Because His Majesty is visiting Her Majesty.
What a coincidence! Then it will save me
the trip to pay respects to His Majesty.
May peace be with Your Highness.
It is of no consequence whether
Her Majesty is feeling unwell today.
What matters is if His Majesty
will feel uneasy if he sees Your Highness today.
Your Highness is wise and
surely understands the importance of this.
Why would you want to displease His Majesty?
I bid Your Highness goodbye.
Your Highness, Lady Cao is here.
Peace to Your Highness.
The scorching heat must be igniting your qi, Your Highness.
I am willing to take any punishment
if it can relieve Your Highness's anger.
You were just a girl selected from a hopeless family!
You weren't even allowed see His Majesty
after you moved in.
If it were not for my help,
how could you have birthed a daughter and been promoted?
Now Concubine Beauté and I are in crisis
all because of your brilliant idea.
How do you have the audacity to say that to me?
I hope Your Highness will
enlighten me on what I've done wrong.
I will take the punishment.
I took your advice
to preempt suspicion by informing
the Empress Dowager of Concubine Beauté's condition.
I don't care that Concubine Beauté
was banished to the Cold Palace,
but I lost my authority to manage the harem.
Isn't this all because you thought you were so smart?
I wish to congratulate Your Highness.
What is there to congratulate me for?
Anything Concubine Beauté uttered
would be considered pure madness.
Whatever Their Majesties suspect is just speculation. There isn't any evidence.
Although Your Highness has temporarily lost power,
your status is safe.
After all, His Majesty remembers the past fondly.
And regaining favor is merely a matter of
His Majesty's whim.
Easy for you to say!
Now that His Majesty is bewitched by Lady Sourire
and the Empress is creating obstacles for me,
I can't even find a chance to see His Majesty.
I will do whatever I can to mend the space
between Your Highness and His Majesty.
What can you do?
His Majesty adores Princess Wenyi.
Rise. Grant her a seat.
I thank Your Highness.
Concubine Beauté is as useless as pretty flowers on a pillow.
But you are much more fortunate
having a daughter by your side.
Unlike me, having no child to depend upon.
I lack virtue and skills.
Were it not for Your Highness's blessing,
Wenyi could not live in peace.
Your Highness loves Wenyi dearly.
She will be a filial daughter to
Your Highness when she grows up.
Look at you,
so immersed in the conversation
that haven't noticed your hair.
I was being hard on you.
- Songzhi.
- Yes.
Attend to Lady Cao's hair in my room.
Yes.
I thank Your Highness.
His Majesty hasn't seen Wenyi for a while.
You should bring her to see His Majesty
at the Palace of Great Benevolence.
Yes.
But I am inarticulate.
I'm afraid I might displease His Majesty.
You don't have to speak.
As long as you can make Wenyi smile and laugh.
There is a phoenix poeny hairpin on my dresser.
Put it on before you go.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.